usyd.edu.au 2005-12-14

# University Web Sites Privacy Statement - The University of Sydney

|  |   
  |  | 

University Web Sites Privacy Statement

The University of Sydney is subject to the [NSW Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act 1998](http://www.austlii.edu.au/au/legis/nsw/consol_act/papipa1998464/index.html) (the Act). The University's [Privacy Management Plan](http://www.usyd.edu.au/arms/pdf/pmp.pdf) [Acrobat format] produced in accordance with section 33 of the Act contains the [University's Privacy Policy](http://www.usyd.edu.au/arms/privacy/policy.htm) and how it will be translated into the University's business practices.

The following sets out how the University will deal with personal information related to the content and use of its web sites. 

|  1\. Collection of Information |   
---|---  

**Information Automatically Logged**  
---  
      | The University may make a record of your visit and logs any of the following information for statistical and business purposes - the user's server address, the user's domain name, IP address, the date and time of the visit, the pages accessed and documents downloaded, the previous site visited and the type of browser used. 

If you are not a University student or a University staff member and you send us a message, the University will record your e-mail address.  
  
**Security Information**  
  | University sites have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information as defined in the University IT Security Policy . 

A login name and password are required to visit secure areas, and before personal information (such as Examination Results) are published on the site, visitors are required to enter their student or staff number as well. This is to ensure that the information are displayed only to the intended person. You should ensure that your password is kept securely and cannot be discovered by anyone else.  
  
**Cookies**  
  | A cookie is information that a Web site puts on your hard disk so that it can remember something about you at a later time. (More technically, it is information for future use that is stored by the server on the client side of a client/server communication.) It is possible to disable the accepting of cookies by your web browser, however doing so may restrict your ability to access some web pages. 

Some University sites are access restricted. These sites may use cookies to deliver content specific to your interest. Cookies may also be used for authentication purposes, and to improve security during a visitor's session online.

Cookies may store the following information: session (numbered key) and duration. A numbered key is a unique server generated number used to identify the current session. The session key can be linked back to a user's login identification.

Unique identifiers (such as login identification) are collected from Web site visitors to verify the user's identity, and for use as account numbers in our record system.

Unique identifiers are also used to store information about visitor's preferences, to enable the dynamic display of the site according to your preferences when you return.  
  
**Surveys**  
  | All academic / research surveys conducted by University staff and / or students, which involve the collection of personal information, will have received approval from the University Ethics Committee. Contact details for the Ethics Committee will be included in each survey instrument. 

Some of our online surveys ask visitors for unique identifiers (like login identification).

Contact information from the surveys may be used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary, for example to follow up on any issues identified by the visitor.  
  
**Registration Forms**  
  | If personal information is collected via a website this will be done by sufficiently secure means. 

Individuals will be provided with alternative means of providing personal information to the University, other than via the website.

For certain applications, our site's registration forms require users to give contact information (like name and email address), and unique identifiers (like login identification and student number).  
  
**External Links**  
  | Some University sites contain links to other sites. The University is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.  

 2\. Use of personal information |   
---|---  

| Personal information you supply on-line will be used by University staff in conducting the business of the University. Such uses include matters related to student administration, provision of services and the dissemination of information to staff, prospective and current students and remaining in contact with graduates. The University may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with a server and to administer a Web site. It is sometimes used to set up individual sessions to provide secure logins. 

Contact information from registration forms is used to get in touch with the visitor to a website when necessary, for example when the visitor is requesting the publication of notice of an event or seeking information about a course offered by the University. For certain applications, for example the online calendar of events, a user's details will be published when they are indicated to be the contact person for a particular event.

Survey data will be used only for stated purposes, as approved by the University Human Ethics Committee.  
  
---|---  

 3\. Disclosure of personal information |   
---|---  

| The University will not disclose personal information concerning you, including your email address, to parties outside the University except in accordance with its [Privacy Policy](http://www.usyd.edu.au/arms/privacy/policy.htm) which conforms to the requirements of the [NSW Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act](http://www.austlii.edu.au/au/legis/nsw/consol_act/papipa1998464/index.html) . Details regarding disclosure of personal information by the University may be found in the Privacy Management Plan . 

Student users may opt-in to having their name and email addresses published as part of the on-line directory of students. The University supplies Email facilities so that it can keep in contact with its students and staff in a timely and cost effective manner  
  
---|---  
**Public Forums**  
| Some University sites may have chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.  

 4\. Data Quality/Access |   
---|---  

| The University will always try to maintain accurate, complete and up-to-date information regarding students and staff. The necessary procedures are in place to facilitate amendments and verification of personal information. If you think that your personal information retained by the University require changing please contact the [Student Centre](http://www.usyd.edu.au/su/studentcentre/) and / or [Personnel Services](http://www.usyd.edu.au/personnel/) as appropriate. 

Full details regarding the means of access to, and correction of, personal information is set out in the University's [Privacy Management Plan](http://www.usyd.edu.au/arms/pdf/pmp.pdf).  
  
---|---  

|
